Y'all start Seth, congrats on being
drafted.
How much contact if any did you have
with the Colts throughout the pre-draft
process? And secondly, what do you think
you can bring to an NFL team?
Um, yeah, no, the the communication
definitely picked up a lot
here recently the closer we got to it.
Um, I had connections with their
with the running back coach, you know,
ever since a couple years ago when he
was at
Texas Tech. You know, we were trying to
make it work there.
And but now man, I'm just excited. I'm
excited to prove everybody wrong. I'm
excited to show everything I could do,
everything I've been doing my whole
life, which is, you know, overcoming
adversity and
you know, disproving people who label me
as the underdog and you know, I'm just
ready. I'm just I'm a I'm going to lay
your back. I'm a playmaker.
And I'm a guy that that can contribute
on all levels to to any offense system.
So, you know, I'm just so blessed to be
a Colt.
Joel, go ahead.
When you say proving people wrong, like,
you know, what are you what are you
thinking of?
You know, I don't know. I feel like you
know, just saying, you know, definitely
slept on. This is definitely
you know, going this late in the draft
was definitely unanticipated you know,
by many teams. But like I said,
everything happens for a reason. And
I'm just ready to make everybody pay
that that that um
that didn't pick me.
Steven.
Hey Seth, what what did you what was
your message to teams when they asked
about, you know, your your history you
had you know, you had the issues a few
years ago. What what did you tell them
to kind of give them some comfort about
the person you are now?
Um, I just wanted them to know that um
you know, that's never who I was and and
who I've been my entire life like you
know, I've always been a staple in my
community. I've always believed in in
leading the youth guiding the youth
being a prime example of hard work and
dedication and
you know, I had a brief season in my
life where unfortunately, you know, I
got away from that and and and it cost
me everything. But you know,
ever since that day I've done everything
that I can with every fiber in my body
to prove that's not who I am. And
that you know, I will continue to be
myself in the values and the values that
I've instilled in myself since since a
very young age. And um
you know, to to trust in the in the
relationships that I built along the way
and and to know that they you know, they
can trust those people and
you know, trust me as well.
James.
Along those lines, do you think that's
why you didn't go as high as perhaps you
thought you could?
Oh, yeah,
you know, most definitely.
Which is you know, obviously it's it's
okay. That's understandable. Like I
said, I'm you know, I'm not a person
that's going to you know hold any grudge
or
sit in and pout about it. You know what
I'm saying? Like I said, I'm a what's
next kind of guy. So, I'm just show up.
I'm just ready to show up and work. And
like I said, help this football team get
to a Super Bowl.
>> [laughter]
>> Abby, go ahead.
Seth, congratulations. You're joining a
running back room that is headed by
Jonathan Taylor who has been an elite
back the last few years. What is an
element of his game that you admire and
hope to learn from with
I definitely think he has a great pace.
You know, I think he he he obviously has
a great feel for tempo and and you know,
shifting his way through the defense.
And it it it would just be good to you
know, learn from a from a
a back that's you know, been that
productive for as long as he has. And
you know, I'm looking forward to to
getting in the room with him.
Jake.
Along those lines, I obviously you know,
Jonathan Taylor one of the marquee backs
in the league.
Colts have been a decent pick on DJ
Giddens last year. What do you tell
yourself when you go into a situation
like that where you want to kind of make
a mark for yourself but at the same time
like
How do you kind of approach it?
Um, I'm a full head of steam kind of
guy. You know, I really only know one
speed and um
you know, that's that's that's full
speed. So, um
you know, I am I am coming in to
compete. I am coming in to to
make my spot. And um you know, I'm a I'm
a guy that you know, I I pride myself in
being a great teammate at the same time
like you know, I I enjoy getting each
other better and healthy competition.
And so,
you know, it's just a balance between
those two things.
And you mentioned you had a relationship
with coach Smith already. Like what what
kind of expectations has he laid out for
you at least initially?
Oh, yeah. I mean, he knows he knows what
I'm coming to do. You know, he knows I'm
coming to work. He knows I'm coming to
produce. Um, he knows I'm a ball player.
So
you know,
you know, we we've we had a a
relationship in recruiting a couple
years ago and
you know, I'm just thankful that that's
continued and and you know, he he's
already gotten a chance to know who I am
as a person and you know, I'm thankful
that he was in that building to watch me
today.
Just a few more, Nathan.
Um, after you spoke a little bit earlier
about
you know, after your your missteps 5
years ago trying to work back toward a a
goal like this, what helped get you back
on the right path? I know some you know,
not everyone would be able to recover
from that and you know, come back and be
drafted in the NFL. What helped you get
back on track and
set your eyes forward to trying to
complete your dreams on making it to the
NFL.
Yeah, first and foremost, obviously my
relationship with God is
you know, an extreme part of my life and
that's my you know, that I believe
that's my primary guidance just in in
all decision-making and all my thought
processes. So knowing the opportunity
and the blessings that he's given me,
you know, prior to even um
you know, after the incident
is something that I just constantly use
to motivate me and and never never take
for granted. You know what I'm saying?
You never know how
little an opportunity can impact your
future you know, down the road. And so
just leaning on the people that that's
always believed in me my whole life and
the people that I've held closest to me
is um
you know, something that that definitely
you know, fueled me along the way.
Kevin.
Congrats, Seth.
So, following the arrest, could you walk
us through school wise that kind of led
to UK there to round out your
your
I guess like five stop career if I have
it right.
Yes, sir. So,
yeah, I mean at one point, you know, I
was I was unfortunately wasn't able to
to get into a junior college.
And
you know, I ended up taking that that
following season off and then um
you know, because of that, you know, I
was I was actually communicating with
the University of Oregon at the time and
um
you know, ended up getting directed to
a buddy of his, the running back coach
who became the head coach at this NAIA
in East Texas called Texas College.
And so,
you know, following two semesters there
um
you know, I didn't feel like it was it
was it was time to re-recruit myself
coming out of junior college.
So, that's when I ended up making my way
to Butler. Um, did one semester there
and
unfortunately had to go you know
handle more of that situation back in
2021. But you know, fortunately from
there was able to
get a spot at New Mexico State. Um
and then you know, from there I
obviously made the decision to to go on
to Kentucky and you know, get back where
I started.
We'll go with Jake and then Joel will be
our last question.
Yes, Seth. Speaking of Kentucky, the
Colts drafted Jaylen Farmer today.
What can you tell us about him as a
player? Like what are the Colts getting
in him and how much Seth help I guess
both of you just with the comfort of
>> yeah. Now, me and him is just alike. You
know what I'm saying? We both
we both dogs. And you know, that's not
that's not that's a word that people
throw around nowadays. But
um, we both truly dudes that you know,
kind of got it out the mud kind of dudes
and
so, you know, we coming to work every
day. You know, we we we enjoy ourselves
you know, off the field just so far as
you know, joking around and stuff like
that. But when we're in the building,
you know, it's all business. And
something that we don't take lightly.
And so,
I'm excited to to to be there with him
and
have a like-minded individual like that.
And then Joel, last question.
You mentioned your faith. Did you come
to faith after the incident or was the
incident sort of a catalyst to bring you
back to God?
Um, I definitely think both.
I definitely think it was a
it was an instance of both.
I've always
I've always known.
I just knew it just became more of an
like you said, like a catalyst more of
an immediacy
that
of something that you know, you can't
ever put on your back burner. And
definitely something that has to be at
the priority of your life and
at the front of your ship. And um
if if you as long as you do that, you'll
never be sailed wrong.